(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
TOKOYAMITOWA 2020 / 01 / 03 DEBUT DATE
TOKOYAMITOWA 3D UNVEILED 2020 / 07 / 26
TOKOYAMITOWA ANNIVERSARY LIVE 2021 / 04 / 17
TOKOYAMITOWA BIRTHDAY FESTIVAL 2021
TOKOYAMITOWA 1ST ANNIVERSARY LIVE
TOKOYAMITOWA 2ND ANNIVERSARY LIVE Scream
聞こえますか？この声が
Can you hear it? This voice.
2ND ANNIVERSARY LIVE GUEST
この声をあなたに届けるために 私は叫び続ける
To deliver this voice to you, I will keep screaming.
Scream
常闇トワ 2周年記念 LIVE Scream
Tokoyami Towa 2nd Anniversary LIVE Scream
Palette
作詞：常闇トワ 作曲：niki
Lyrics: Tokoyami Towa / Composition: niki
風に吹かれて
Blown by the wind
誰も気付かぬよう
So that no one notices
区別がつかない
Indistinguishable
モノクロの世界
A monochrome world
色を足しても
Even if I add color
何も見えなくて
I can't see anything
まるで私は
It's as if I
息を止めていた
Had been holding my breath
もう一度遠くても
Once more, even if it's far
叶えたい
I want to make it come true
私は
I...
この世界思いも
...want to embrace this world
抱きしめていたいのに
And its feelings, and yet...
夢のキャンバスに
On the canvas of dreams
描き続ける意味は
The meaning of continuing to draw
この胸に輝いている
Is the story shining
ストーリー
In my heart
与えることに　意味などないけど
There's no meaning in giving, but...
拾い集めた　欠片失うの
I lose the fragments I've gathered.
閉じた夜は　その冷たさを
On closed nights, that coldness...
溶かして　手を伸ばした
...is melted as I reach out my hand.
もういいよ　遠くても　届けたい　私は
It's okay, even if it's far, I want to reach it, I...
受け止めていく　涙も　抱きしめていたいのに
...will accept everything.
I want to embrace even the tears, and yet...
夢のキャンバスに　心込めるのは
Putting my heart into the canvas of dreams...
この空に　描き出していく　ストーリー
...is a story I'm drawing in this sky.
そして夜は　その冷たさを
And then the night, that coldness...
溶かして　手を伸ばした
...is melted as I reach out my hand.
もういいの　遠くても　叶えたい　私の
It's okay, even if it's far, I want to fulfill my...
声なき世界　思いを　言葉で包んだ
...voiceless world's feelings, wrapped in words.
夢のキャンバスに　彩り足していく
Adding colors to the canvas of dreams...
この胸に　今輝いて
...is shining in this heart now.
強くなくてもいい
It's okay not to be strong.
壊れかけてもいい
It's okay even if it starts to break.
この心は　永遠に羽ばたいて
This heart will flap its wings forever.
響くように　塗り替えていく　Palette
To resonate, I'm repainting it, Palette.
作詞・作曲・編曲・マスタリング：niki
Lyrics, Music, Arrangement, Mastering: niki
はい！あけましておめでとうございますー！
Hi! Happy New Year!
はぁー。こんやっぴー、ホロライブ4期生の常闇トワ様だー！
Haa. Kon-yappi! It's Hololive 4th Gen's
Tokoyami Towa-sama!
はい、ということで皆さん、緊張しております、常闇トワ、2周年です今日は！
Yes, so everyone, I'm nervous,
Tokoyami Towa is at her 2nd anniversary today!
みんなありがとうー！
Thank you everyone!
配信始まる前からいっぱい素敵なコメントいただいて、
I received many wonderful comments even before
the stream started,
もうめっちゃ緊張してんだよな、今。本当にすごい緊張してるんですよ。
and I'm really nervous now.
I'm actually incredibly nervous.
なんたって、てかあの、知らない人の方が多いかもしれないけど、
Because, well, there might be many who
don't know, but,
トワちょっと休止してて、「あ、ちょっと無理だ、休むわ」って言って、
I was on a short break. I said,
"Ah, this is a bit too much, I'm taking a break,"
今日久しぶりの配信なんです。イェーイ！
and today is my first stream in a while. Yay!
ヤッホー！ありがとう。
Yoho! Thank you.
はい、1発目、「Palette」歌いました。これね、
Yes, for the first song, I sang "Palette". This,
劇場版エンディングとか言われてすごい光栄なんですけれども、
people call it a "movie ending theme" and
it's a great honor,
エンディングではなく、今回オープニングで歌わせてもらいました。
but it's not the ending, I sang it as
the opening this time.
もう演出とかもね、すごいもうこだわって。
I was really particular about the production too.
「Palette」はね、結構思い入れのある曲でして、
"Palette" is a song I have a lot of feelings for,
ま、いろんなものと出会って前に進んでくっていう曲なので、
well, it's a song about meeting various things
and moving forward,
1発目にこの曲を持ってきて、エモい感じにしちゃいました。イェーイ！
so I brought this song as the first one
to create an emotional vibe. Yay!
で、なんと、なんと、なんと！見て、ステージ見てくれた？
And, what's more, what's more!
Look, did you see the stage?
ステージ！見て、ビビと、あと見て。
The stage! Look, Bibi, and look at this.
おい！TMTって書いてあるー。ふふふ。
Hey! It says TMT. Hehehe.
あの電光掲示板みたいな、あれ、「曲名載せてくださいね」って言ったんだけど、
That electric bulletin board thing, I said
"Please put the song titles there,"
なんかTMTって書いてある。よく分からんて。
but it says TMT for some reason. I don't get it.
このね、あのステージなんですけれども、ファンアートから、
This stage, actually, it's based on fan art,
あの、3Dでファンアートを作ってくださった方がいて、
someone created fan art in 3D,
「これちょっとモチーフ使用していいですか？」ってリプしたら、
and when I replied asking
"Can I use this as a motif?"
「え、どうぞどうぞトワ様どうぞ」っていう形で使わせて、
they were like "Eh, please, please,
Towa-sama, go ahead",
参考にね、作っていただきました。イェーイ！
so it was made with that as a reference. Yay!
おい、TMTコメント多すぎだろ。
Hey, there are too many TMT comments.
はい、あと今日のハッシュタグはこちら、「#常闇トワ2周年記念」
Yes, and today's hashtag is this,
"#TokoyamiTowa2ndAnniversary"
になってます。これでいっぱい呟いて、
is what it is. Please tweet a lot with this,
新年からトレンド入りさせてくれたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you could get it trending
from the start of the year.
はい、そしてね、今日のサムネイルはチョコ庵先生に描いていただきましたー！
Yes, and today's thumbnail was drawn by
Chocoan-sensei!
これめちゃめちゃ...
This is incredibly...
そう、そうなんだよね。あのさ、
Yeah, that's right. You know...
ホロライブのさ、ボイスでさ、ハロウィンボイスがあったときに、
when Hololive had those Halloween voices...
たまたまね、トワがそのハロウィンボイスの絵だったんだけど、
Towa's Halloween voice happened to have that illustration,
それをちょこ先生が描いてくれてて、
and Choco-sensei was the one who drew it.
「うわ、めっちゃ好きなイラストだ！」と思って、もうお願いしちゃいました。
I thought, "Wow, I love this illustration!" so I asked her to do this.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
あと、ロゴもね！
And the logo too!
はい、ロゴはね、ホロライブ好きな人だったら結構見るんじゃないでしょうか、
The logo... if you're a Hololive fan, you've probably seen it before.
柊先生に描いていただきました。
It was designed by Hiiragi-sensei.
作っていただきました。ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for creating it.
はい。
Yes.
まぁ、軽くになっちゃうんですけど紹介もしまして、
Well, that was a brief introduction,
この後はね、曲歌って、ライブということで、
but from here on, we're moving into the live performance part!
もっともっといっぱいあるので、楽しんでいってください。
There's still a lot more in store, so please enjoy!
はい。
Yes.
まだまだ楽しんでもらっていけば、うれ...
I hope you keep enjoying the show...
おっと... 言葉がぐちゃぐちゃじゃないか。
Whoops... my words are getting all jumbled.
はい、この後もね、楽しんでください！
Anyway, please keep enjoying the live!
ということで、次はなんと、
And so, next up is...
ゲストパーソン！
Guest performers!
Dreaming Days
少しずつ 近づいて
Little by little, I'm getting closer
いるよ 夢に見た ときめき
to the excitement I dreamed of
広がっていく 世界中に
It's spreading throughout the world
みんなを笑顔にさせる キラメキを
A sparkle that makes everyone smile
一人じゃないから ライバルがいるから
Because I'm not alone, because I have rivals
競い合うことすら 楽しくなっちゃうんだよ
Even competing becomes fun
うんとだよ Believe myself
Yeah, believe myself
Believe myself!
未来へ 走り出したら Fantastic
When I start running towards the future, it's Fantastic
夢を咲かせて Our future
Make our dreams bloom, Our future
一歩一歩 踏み出した
Step by step, we set out
遠くを目指そう
aiming for the distance
信じる力が 心の Happiness
The power of belief is the heart's happiness
全力で楽しもう
Let's enjoy it with all our might
それはいつか きっと
It will surely, one day
大きな夢 叶えるから
make a big dream come true
Dreaming Days
答えのない 道をゆく
Going down a path with no answers
誰も見たことの ない世界
A world no one has ever seen before
連れてゆくよ みんなのこと
I'll take everyone there with me
覚悟はいいかな
Are you ready?
手を離さないで
Don't let go of my hand
一人じゃないから
Because you're not alone
君が見ているから
Because you're watching
初めての 挑戦すら
Even my first challenge
楽しくなっちゃうんだよ
becomes fun
Believe myself!
奇跡を 巻き起こすんだ グロリアス
Let's cause a miracle, Glorious
夢に近づいて My story
Getting closer to my dream, My story
とても小さな つぼみが
Even if it's a very small bud
花咲かせるまで
until it blooms
挑戦し続けるんだ ブリリアント
I'll keep challenging, Brilliant
全力で飛び込もう
Let's dive in with all our might
ほんの少しだけの
Just a little bit
勇気が今 僕を照らしたんだ
of courage has shined upon me now
Dreaming Days
選んできた 未来の選択肢
The choices for the future I've made
すべてがほら 私を作った
Look, they all made me who I am
選ぶことの なかった過去さえ
Even the past that I didn't choose
大事な意味が あったと気づいたよ
I realized that it had an important meaning
選ぶことの なかった過去さえ
Even the past that I didn't choose
大事な意味が あったと気づいたよ
I realized that it had an important meaning
涙を流した 数が Emotion
The number of tears shed is emotion
熱い心が Over heat
A hot heart is overheating
本気だからこそ 燃える
Because I'm serious, I'm burning up
トップになりたい
I want to be at the top
未来へ 走り出したら Fantastic
When I start running towards the future, it's Fantastic
全力で楽しもう
Let's enjoy it with all our might
それはいつか きっと
It will surely, one day
大きな夢 叶えるから
make a big dream come true
Dreaming Days
Oh yeah!
走り続けていくんだ グレイトフル
I'll keep running, Grateful
一人じゃ届かない 高みへ
To heights that can't be reached alone
Yeah!!
え、可愛い、トワたち。
Wow, you guys look so cute.
え、可愛かった。
That was so cute.
凄かった。
It was amazing.
トワ先輩、2周年、おめでとう！
Towa-senpai, happy 2nd anniversary!
凄い、コラボ1発目にどエモいのを持ってきてしまいました。
Wow, I brought something really emotional for the first collaboration.
いやもう、クライマックス感、本当に、もうラストみたいな感じだったけどね、本当に。
I mean, it felt like the climax, really, like it was already the finale.
ラストみたいな響き、クライマックス感凄かった。
It sounded like the finale, the climax feeling was incredible.
なんか良いのかな、どうしようかなって思ったけど、やっぱりこういう1発目にボーン！っていうのを持ってきたら、
I wondered if it was okay, but as expected, starting with a 'boom' like this...
なんか、そんな1発目に選ばれちゃいました。
We were chosen for the very first performance.
選ばれちゃった！嬉しい！
We were chosen! I'm so happy!
呼んでくれてありがとう！
Thanks for inviting us!
ちょっと不思議なメンバーじゃない？
Isn't this a bit of an unusual lineup?
このメンバーになった理由を。
Tell us why you chose this lineup.
まず、そう。AZKi先輩とは、本当に歌が凄い好きで、一緒に歌いたかったんだけど、やっぱり二人とかで歌うのはトワもドキドキしたし、
First, well. I really love AZKi-senpai's singing and wanted to sing with her, but singing as a duo made me nervous...
コラボとかも誘いたいときとか誘えないくらい、ちょっとドキドキしてたから、
I was so nervous I couldn't even bring myself to invite her for a collab...
勇気を出して誘ってみて、
So I plucked up the courage and asked her.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
で、あとは、ねねねとロボ子先輩は、周年配信とか、誕生日配信、記念配信の時に呼びたかったんだけど、
And then, for Nene-ne and Roboco-senpai, I wanted to invite them for my anniversary and birthday streams before...
それまでまだちょっと呼べてなかったから、今回、今日、一緒に歌いたいと思って。
But I hadn't had the chance yet, so I really wanted us to sing together today.
嬉しい！やっと呼ばれた！ありがとう！
I'm so happy! Finally invited! Thank you!
もう本当に、ハーモニーも凄く良かった。
Really, the harmony was amazing as well.
良かったよね！凄く良かった。
It was, wasn't it! It was so good.
トワも、1曲目からエモすぎて、涙が出そうになっちゃって、
I was getting so emotional from the very first song, I almost cried...
早い早い！
Too early!
本当に幸せ者だなって、こんな祝ってもらえて。
I feel so lucky to be celebrated like this.
ゴンドラも凄かった！ゴンドラやばかった！眺めが良かった！
The gondola was amazing! It was incredible! The view was great!
めっちゃ良かったね。
It was really great.
あの、降りてくるところも凄く良かった。
The part where we were descending was also great.
扉が開くところめちゃめちゃ可愛かった！二人ずつね。
The part where the doors opened was so cute! Two at a time.
そう、あれめっちゃ可愛かった、みんな。
Yeah, everyone looked so cute there.
これは、本当に皆さんのおかげです。
This is all thanks to everyone.
ありがとう！呼んでくれて！こちらこそありがとう！
Thank you for inviting us! No, thank YOU!
でもね、最後、次もあるということで、
But anyway, there's more coming up next...
そうだ、まだ始まったばっかり！
Right, it's only just begun!
こんなエモいんだけど、始まったばっかりだから！
It's already this emotional, but we're just getting started!
まだまだあるから！
There's still plenty more!
この始まりの、写真も、こうやって撮って、
Let's take a photo like this to mark the start...
お別れします。
We'll be heading off now.
集まれ集まれ！
Get closer, get closer!
ありがとう！この後もお楽しみに！
Thank you! Please look forward to the rest!
でいり～だいあり～　おぼえちゃおう
Daily Diary, let's remember it
青春実況中　挑戦配信中
Broadcasting youth live, streaming our challenges
ほらね、楽しいを　発見
Look, I discovered fun
また新しい「好き」が見つかったよ　なに、なに？超気になる！
Found a new 'like' again. What, what? I'm so curious!
近所にできたカフェの　ケーキ
The cake from the cafe that opened nearby
なんか凄く美味しかったんだよ　これこれ！待ってたんだって！
It was somehow really delicious. This is it! I was waiting for this!
知らなかったゲームや
Games I didn't know
聴いたことない歌
Songs I've never heard
ちょっと気になったら手を伸ばそう
If you're a bit curious, reach out your hand
おいで、一緒に遊ぼう　（配信！）
Come on, let's play together (Stream!)
充電器持ってきてみよう
Let's try bringing a charger
ホラーゲームやってみよう
Let's try playing a horror game
あの曲歌ってみよう　ぜんぶが、もう楽しいの！
Let's try singing that song. Everything is already so fun!
窓の向こうの　笑顔に手を振っちゃう
I wave my hand to the smiles across the window
アニメ視聴中
Watching anime
発見、モブのキャラに推せるポテンシャル　なんでも観てみるわ
Discovery, a background character with potential. I'll watch anything.
積み上げた漫画や
Piled up manga
思いついた新ネタ
New gags I came up with
当たんない天気予報もきっと
Even the weather forecast that doesn't hit
面白いことになるんだよ　（配信！）
Will turn into something interesting (Stream!)
見て見て！今日の朝　目覚まし鳴らなくて
Look, look! This morning, the alarm didn't go off
寝過ごしちゃったのは　昨晩の生放送！
The reason I overslept was last night's live stream!
凄く楽しくて　寝付けなかったんだよ
It was so fun that I couldn't fall asleep
いいことなんて そう起こらないリアル
The reality is that good things don't happen that often
だけどそのエッセンス
But that essence
仮想の世界 夢に替えて
Turn the virtual world into a dream
毎日がパラダイス
Every day is paradise
思い切り遊んで笑っちゃおう！
Let's play to our heart's content and laugh!
どんな毎日も 楽しくなっちゃうんだ
Every day becomes fun
だって、いつだって ほらあなたが待ってるの
Because, look, you're always waiting
みんなで毎日を 出会えた嬉しいを
Let's share every day, the joy of meeting each other
みんなと一緒に 気分はね、もう最高潮！
Together with everyone, our spirits are already at their peak!
窓の向こうの笑顔に手を振って
Waving to the smiles beyond the window
配信でとどける our daily dairy
Delivering our daily dairy through the stream
daily dairy
届けよう
Let's deliver it
はーい！やったー！
Yay! We did it!
え、うまくいきましたね？
Eh, it went well, didn't it?
いきましたねー！
It did!
いけましたねー！
We made it!
はい、ということで...っていつも言っちゃうんだけど、ということで、
Yes, and so... I always say that, but anyway,
はい、かなトワししらみで「daily dairy」を歌わせていただきましたー！
Yes, we, Kanatowa-shishilamy, sang "daily dairy"!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
ありがとう！いや、かなたんもこの前おめでとう！
Thank you! No, Kanatan, congratulations recently too!
おめでとう！あ、ありがとう！
Congratulations! Ah, thank you!
やったー！ということで、そして、あけましておめでとうございます！
Yay! So, and also, Happy New Year!
いや、なんだかんだかなトワとかししらみとかそういう組み合わせあったけど、この4人で集まることは、
You know, we've had units like Kanatowa or Shishilamy, but gathering as these four...
そう、初めてかも！初めて！
Might be the first time! The first!
珍しい！なんでみんなそんな後ろ行ってんの？もっと来てよ！
It's rare! Why is everyone going to the back? Come closer!
いいのかい？いいのかい？どうですか、この並び。結構ね、いい感じじゃない？
Is it okay? Is it okay? How's this lineup? It's pretty good, right?
どう？なんか見たことあるようで実は初。そんな感じだよね。
How is it? It feels like we've seen it before, but it's actually the first. That's the vibe.
「あれ、この4人でコラボしたことあるよね？」って言ったら「いや、なくない？」って。
If you asked, "Wait, haven't these four collabed before?", the answer is "No, haven't we?"
「ないわ」「ないか」。お出かけとかしたいね。かなたんのファッションの...
"No we haven't." "I see." I want to go out or something. Like, for Kanatan's fashion...
え？みんなとファッションしてくれるんですか？
Eh? Are you going to do fashion with me?
ちょっと待って。ファッションね。お買い物行きますか、じゃあ。
Wait a minute. Fashion, right. Shall we go shopping then?
お買い物行きたい！でもこの中で一番おしゃれなの誰だと思う？
I want to go shopping! But who do you think is the most stylish among us?
いや、私！降ろせ降ろせ！許されへんぞ！そんなわけねぇだろ！
No, it's me! Put your hands down! That won't be forgiven! No way!
やっぱりラミィかな？でもトワ先輩だってファッションのってプロフィールに書いてますし。
Maybe Lamy? But look, even Towa-senpai has "fashion" written in her profile.
やめろ！やめろ！持ち上げんじゃねえ！
Stop! Stop! Don't flatter me!
すいません、すいません。おめでとうございます。
Sorry, sorry. Congratulations.
え、でも待って。トワさん、ちょっとこの4人で写真みたいなスクショ撮りたい。
Eh, but wait. I want to take a picture, like a screenshot, with these four.
撮りたい！どうやって並ぶ？かなたん前行こ。あ、じゃあこうしますか。いいじゃーん！
I want to! How should we line up? Kanatan, go to the front. Oh, like this? Nice!
いい感じじゃない？撮って撮って！イェーイ！
Isn't this good? Take it, take it! Yay!
ま、こんな感じでまったり...あれ、急にテンションダウン？
Well, in this relaxed way... huh, sudden drop in tension?
いいんだよ、みんなと歌えればいいから。これからもよろしくお願いします。
It's okay, as long as I can sing with everyone. Please look forward to working with us.
なまいきな後輩と、なまいきじゃないが、なまいきな二人と、
With the cheeky juniors—well, not cheeky, but with the two cheeky ones...
天使な、かなたんと。センスがね、完璧なかなたんと。
And with the angelic Kanatan. With the Kanatan whose sense is perfect.
耳がよく聞こえないな。耳痛くなってきちゃった。はっ？
I can't hear very well. My ears are starting to hurt. What?
はい、ということで、かなトワししらみで「daily dairy」でしたー！バイバーイ！
Yes, so, that was "daily dairy" by Kanatowa-shishilamy! Bye-bye!
Moonlight Merry-Go-Round Candy-Go-Round
夢のようなスピードで Escort
Escort at a dream-like speed
時の流れはいつでもゆっくり
The flow of time is always slow
だけどハートの 動くスピード 気まぐれは UP
But the speed at which the heart moves—the whim is "up"
待っていてね
Wait for me
この場所へ　ちゃんと届くように
so it reaches this place properly.
君の Clap Clap Clap
Your Clap Clap Clap
Everybody Clap Hands Up
空想ヘドライブ
Imaginary Drive
Moonlight メリーゴーランド　Candy-Go-Round
Moonlight merry-go-round, Candy-Go-Round
レディゴーランド　夢のようなスピードで　飛び立とう
ready-go-round, let's take off at a dreamlike speed
歌に　乗り込めば　行けるんだ
If we ride on the song, we can go
タイムスリップも　止められない
Even time slips can't be stopped
Starlight メリーゴーランド　Candy-Go-Round
Starlight merry-go-round, Candy-Go-Round
パラレルワールド　始まりのベルが鳴り響く夜に
parallel world, on the night when the starting bell rings out
迎えに　行くから
Because I'm coming to pick you up
同じビートで　一つのナンバー　奏でよう
Let's play one number with the same beat
ハートを1ミリでも動かせば
If you move your heart even by a millimeter
キセキ起こす　大きな一歩に繋がるから
It will lead to a big step that makes miracles happen
つまらない時は　ワクワクをクリックしてみよう
When you're bored, try clicking on excitement
君と Dance Dance Dance
With you Dance Dance Dance
Everybody Shall We Dance
ステップ踏んでパーティーしよう
Let's step and have a party
Starlight メリーゴーランド　Candy-Go-Round
Starlight merry-go-round, Candy-Go-Round
ワンダーランド　出かけたい場所へ連れて行くよ
wonderland, I'll take you to the place you want to go
瞳　閉じたら　合図なんだ
When you close your eyes, that's the signal
妄想トリップも　止められない
Even delusion trips can't be stopped
Starlight メリーゴーランド　Candy-Go-Round
Starlight merry-go-round, Candy-Go-Round
カラフルナイト　どんな距離だって超えて会いに行く
colorful night, I'll cross any distance to come see you
夜空を　見上げて
Look up at the night sky
ドラマチックで　忘れられない　今にしよう
Let's make this moment dramatic and unforgettable
起きたら覚めない　魔法をかけるから　始めよう　ステージを
I'll cast a spell that won't break when you wake up, so let's start the stage
君の胸の　ドキドキ
The throbbing in your chest
嘘じゃないよ　リアルなんだよ
It's not a lie, it's real
星も嬉しくて　飛び回っているよ　リズムを合わせるように
The stars are happy and flying around, as if matching the rhythm
とびきりな夢を
An extraordinary dream
君と (君と) 君と (君と) 一緒に
With you (With you) With you (With you) Together
Moonlight メリーゴーランド　Candy-Go-Round
Moonlight merry-go-round, Candy-Go-Round
レディゴーランド　夢のようなスピードで　飛び立とう
ready-go-round, let's take off at a dreamlike speed
歌に　乗り込めば　行けるんだ
If we ride on the song, we can go
タイムスリップも　止められない
Even time slips can't be stopped
Starlight メリーゴーランド　Candy-Go-Round
Starlight merry-go-round, Candy-Go-Round
パラレルワールド　始まりのベルが鳴り響く夜に
parallel world, on the night when the starting bell rings out
迎えに　行くから
Because I'm coming to pick you up
同じビートで　一つのナンバー　奏でよう
Let's play one number with the same beat
せーの！
Ready, set...
うおーーーーい！
*Loud Screams*
ちょ、待って待って！　練習と違うんやが！
W-wait, wait! This is different from practice!
え？
Eh?
何のこと？
What are you talking about?
みんなで練習したじゃんね、あそこで。
We practiced together, right there.
せーの！
Ready, set...
うおーーーーい！
*Screams*
あそこはさ、こういう感じで可愛く跳ねようって言ってたじゃん！
Back there, we said we'd jump cutely like this!
え、何のこと言ってるの？
Eh, what are you talking about?
せーの！
Ready, set...
うおーーーーい！
*Screams*
ちょ、待って。モニター見て。みんな分かるけど、トワずっとこうやってたから！
Wait. Look at the monitor. You all can tell, Towa was doing this the whole time!
あははは！
*Laughs*
なーにを話してたの？
What were you talking about?
トワがトイレに行ってる時に、本番でこうやろーって言ったんだよ。
While Towa was in the bathroom, we decided to do this in the actual performance.
そう、ドッキリ大成功！　イェーイ！
Yeah, prank successful! Yay!
マジでびっくりしたんだけど！
I was seriously surprised!
急にこんなん…急になんか…ええーっ！
Suddenly it became like this... suddenly... what?!
逆にその動きできないんだけど！
I can't even do that movement!
やってごらん？
Try it!
まずはこのフワッてステップの感じから、
Start with this light stepping feeling,
だんだん大胆に。はい！　はい！　はい！　はい！
then gradually bolder. Go! Go! Go! Go!
いいよトワ、輝いてるよ！
Nice, Towa, you're shining!
やだーっ！　今日こんなことで呼ばれたくなかったのにー！
Nooo! I didn't want to be called for something like this today!
違うよ、重い想いで呼んでくれたんだよ。
No, they called you with deep feelings.
2周年おめでとう！
Happy 2nd Anniversary!
やりすぎだよ…え、おかしいな。
You guys are doing too much... eh, something's weird.
それが僕たちにとって精一杯のお祝いだったんだからね
That was our best way to celebrate for you.
そうだ、そうだ！
That's right, that's right!
じゃあなんかトワが悪いみたいじゃん...
Then it sounds like I'm the bad guy here...
もう仲間じゃん、だって。できるようになったし
You're already one of us, see. Since you can do it now.
なんか Okayu がさ、冒険のクエストのさ、もう君がそれができるようになったら仲間だね、みたいな。そういう風に見えてきたんだけど
It's like Okayu-senpai is saying, like in an adventure quest, "Now that you can do that, you're a comrade."
大丈夫、チュートリアルも完璧だったし、大丈夫だよ
It's okay, the tutorial was perfect, so you'll be fine.
じゃあ... いっ、いくぞー！
Alright... let's go!
おー！
Yeah!
OkayuとMioちゃんと、あとPekoraちゃんと、トワで『Candy-Go-Round』でした！ バイバーイ！
That was "Candy-Go-Round" with Okayu, Mio-chan, Pekora-chan, and Towa! Bye-bye!
いつの間にか見つけてた　遠い夢
A distant dream I found before I knew it
一人じゃ見えなかった景色
A scenery I couldn't see alone
波打つ風の音と　加速してく想いに
To the sound of the waving wind and the accelerating feelings
戸惑いを覚えた
I felt a sense of bewilderment
ずっと追いかけた　理想の姿は
The ideal form I kept chasing after
まだ届かなくて遠いけど
Is still far and out of reach, but...
きっとこの瞬間も　かけがえないみんなで
Surely this moment too, with everyone who is irreplaceable
共に行くよ
We'll go together
手を繋いで
Holding hands
精一杯　輝き出そうとして
Trying our best to start shining
夢の場所へ
To the place of dreams
駆け抜けていく
We're running through
僕たちの青春の光は
The light of our youth
誰にも止められないよ
Can't be stopped by anyone
笑い合う分だけ
Just as much as we laugh together
溢れる涙さえ
Even the overflowing tears
ほら輝かせ　明日へ運ぶから
Look, let them shine, because they'll carry us to tomorrow
君の隣で
By your side
僕たちは世界を超えていく
We'll cross over the world
迎えに行くよ
We're coming to get you
まだ見えない明日も
Even the tomorrow we can't see yet
煌めきに変えてきっと
Will surely turn into a sparkle
僕たちが未来へと
We, towards the future...
連れて行くから！
Will take you there!
背伸びしては手を伸ばす　憧れの
Stretching and reaching out for what I long for
行き先標す星になろう
Let's become the stars that mark the destination
躓くその度に　手を差し伸べ合えたら
If we can reach out to each other every time we stumble
すぐに届くはずさ
We should reach it soon
そっと踏み出した　小さな勇気が
The small courage that gently took a step forward
もう消えないように繋げよう
Let's connect it so it doesn't disappear anymore
不安な愛しさも　大切に抱きしめて
Even the anxious dearness, embrace it dearly
共に行くよ
We'll go together
目を合わせて
Meeting our eyes
精一杯　羽ばたく希望へ
Towards the hope that flutters with all its might
飛び出せるよ
We can jump out
突き抜けていく
We're breaking through
僕たちの透き通る情熱は
Our transparent passion
まだまだ止められないよ
Can't be stopped yet
ありきたりな今日こそ
It's precisely this ordinary today
輝きに変えてもっと
That we'll turn into a sparkle even more
僕たちがいつまでも
We, forever...
背中押すから！
Will push you from behind!
ずっと一人で描いてた
I was always drawing by myself
いつか届くこの場所を
This place that I'd reach someday
憧れを今
The longing now...
大好きを紡ぎ
Weaving our favorites
どこまでも高く
Rising as high as we can
あすいろの空へ
To the sky the color of tomorrow
駆け抜けていく
We're running through
僕たちの青春の光は
The light of our youth
誰にも止められないよ
Can't be stopped by anyone
笑い合う分だけ
Just as much as we laugh together
溢れる涙さえ
Even the overflowing tears
ほら輝かせ　明日へ運ぶから
Look, let them shine, because they'll carry us to tomorrow
君の隣で
By your side
僕たちは世界を超えていく
We'll cross over the world
迎えに行くよ
I'm coming to pick you up
まだ見えない明日も
Even the tomorrow we can't see yet
煌めきに変えてきっと
I'll surely turn it into a sparkle
僕たちが未来へと
As we head towards the future
果てのない未来へと
Towards the endless future
連れて行くから
Because we'll take you there
イエーイ！
Yeah!
どうだった？
How was it?
良かったよ！あのね、いつもね、いつもね、
It was great! You know, always, always,
前回の生誕祭の時に「いつもとは、とわー、ということで」をすごい乱用してたから
I overused "as always, it's Towa, and with that" during my last birthday stream
その後、何を言おうかすごい悩んだ
So I was really worried about what to say after that
「ということで」禁止をしたの。「ということで」禁止！
I banned "and with that." "And with that" is banned!
あの、すごい空白の時間が流れた
Um, there was a long period of silence
え、ちょっとみんな揃おう
Hey, let's all get together
イエーイ！あ、やる？オッケーオッケー。
Yeah! Oh, we doing it? Okay, okay.
えっ、えっと、とわたち、せーの！スタッフでーす！
Um, okay, we are... one, two! STAFF!
S! T! A! F! F! スタッフ！
S! T! A! F! F! STAFF!
バラバラじゃん！バラバラじゃん！もう完全に一致したっていう演出があって、忘れてて
We're all over the place! There was supposed to be a perfectly synchronized performance, but I forgot
確かに。ちょっと持ってたもんね。
True. You were holding onto it a bit.
意外なメンバーなんだけど、そう、あのBLOOMで、その「あすいろClearSky」を歌ってない3人、
It's an unexpected group, but yeah, for Bloom, the three who haven't sung "Asuiro Clear Sky",
はい！歌ってませーん！歌ってませーん！
Yes! I haven't sung it! I haven't sung it!
すいちゃんとあやめちゃんとフブちゃん歌ってない3人を集めて、シャッフルユニットっていう形でやらせていただきました！
Suichan, Ayame-chan, and Fubuchan—the three who haven't sung it—formed a shuffle unit!
凄く良かったんじゃない？めっちゃバランス良かったよね。楽しかった。
Wasn't it great? The balance was really good. It was fun.
でも高かったでしょ。めっちゃ高かった。
But it was high-pitched, wasn't it? It was really high.
すいちゃんめっちゃ張り上げるやん！「未来へとー！連れて行くからー！」って。あんな苦しさ感じさせない。
Suichan, you really belted it out! "To the future! Because we'll take you there!" It looked effortless.
そうだよね。あと凄くダンスもさ、簡単ではあるけどみんな凄く揃ってて綺麗だったよね。
Right. And the dance, too—it's simple, but everyone was so synchronized and beautiful.
楽しかったね。ありがとうございます。
It was fun. Thank you very much.
今年もよろしくお願いします。あ、よろしくお願いします。
I look forward to working with you this year too. Oh, me too.
毎回これを言う感じだよね。あけましておめでとうございます。
We say this every time, don't we? Happy New Year.
最後にちょっとみんなで写真撮らない？
Want to take a photo together at the end?
あ、これこれ。さっきのスタッフのポーズで。
Oh, this one. With the STAFF pose from earlier.
このバージョンと、違うバージョンも撮る？トワ2周年おめでとう！ありがとう！
This version, and should we take another too? Towa, congrats on your 2nd anniversary! Thanks!
じゃあもう1回可愛いバージョン撮ろう。
Then let's take a cute version one more time.
可愛い！可愛い！もっと寄ろうよ。
Cute! Cute! Let's get closer.
プリプリ！あ、いい感じ。イエーイ！
Puri-puri! Oh, that's good. Yeah!
いつも通りがいいな。そうね、いつも通りがいいね。
The usual way is best. Yeah, the usual way is good.
ということで、あ！言っちゃった！
And with that... oh! I said it!
あれ、絶対言うと思った！やべー、めっちゃ早かったわ、反応が。構えてたよ。
I knew you would say it! Crap, that was a fast reaction. I was bracing for it.
はいということで！ではすいちゃんとあやめちゃんとフブちゃんとトワで「あすいろClearSky」でした！
Yes, and with that! That was Suichan, Ayame-chan, Fubuchan, and Towa with "Asuiro Clear Sky"!
バイバーイ！ありがとう！
Bye-bye! Thank you!
さあ、ゲストパートいかがだったでしょうか！
Well then, how did you like the guest part?!
凄く良かったんじゃないですか？トワはやっぱりプロデューサーセンスがあるんじゃないかと勝手に思っております。
Wasn't it great? I personally think that I might have some producer sense.
はい、まあそのゲストパートとか、そういう色々ね、もうすっごいあったんだよ！
Yeah, well, regarding that guest part and various other things... a lot happened!
ね、スタッフさん、みんな。
Right, staff members, everyone?
色々あった！ゲストのみんな！色々あった上で、今回こういう感じで凄くエモいのができました！
A lot happened! After everything that happened, we were able to make something really emotional like this!
この裏話を聞きたい人は後日配信をするので、よかったら後日配信見に来てね！
If you want the behind-the-scenes stories, I'll be streaming later, so please come watch!
イエーイ！ゲストめっちゃ良かった！ありがとう！
Yeah! The guests were so good! Thank you!
あともう皆と歌えて本当によかったです。
I'm so glad I could sing with everyone.
まあ、そのゲストの話は後日するとして
Well, I'll talk more about the guests another day...
ま、皆さんこれぐらいの時間だったら分かると思いますよね？
Everyone, I think you know what time it is, right?
はい、何があるか。はい、こちら！ドーン！
Yes, what's coming up. Yes, this! Boom!
常闇トワ 活動2周年記念
Tokoyami Towa 2nd Anniversary Celebration
（笑）長いよー！はい、グッズです！
(Laughing) That was a long wait! Yes, it's the goods!
どうしよう、明日新年から頭ちょっとヤバいかもしれない。
What should I do? My head might be a bit crazy starting from the New Year tomorrow.
はい、2周年記念グッズが発売されます！
Yes, 2nd anniversary commemorative goods will be on sale!
4種類ありまして、ランダムのラバーストラップ
There are 4 types. First, the random rubber straps...
トワのモチーフボディバッグ。これすごいから後で実物見るね。
...and the Towa-motif body bag. This is great, we'll look at the real thing later.
あとは眷属の3連ブレスレット。あとはマスク
Then there's the Kenzoku 3-layer bracelet, and the mask.
が入ったセットを、フルセットを買っていただきますと
If you buy the full set containing all of these items...
サインとメッセージ入りのダイカットポストカードがあなたのお手元に入ります。
...you'll receive a die-cut postcard with my signature and message.
トーク！トーク力よ！
Talk! It's all about talk power!
今年もねトーク力を鍛えていきたいと思っております。
I want to continue training my talk power this year as well.
はい、では細かい内容はこちら！ドーン！
Alright, here are the details! Boom!
ランダム ラバーストラップ 1種 (全4種)
Random Rubber Strap 1 type (total 4 types)
ランダムストラップはこちら、4種類ありまして
The random straps are here, there are 4 types...
見て、アイドル衣装のトワと
...look, Towa in her idol outfit...
お正月衣装のトワ
...Towa in her New Year outfit...
あとは通常衣装のトワ
...Towa in her default outfit...
あとは新衣装のトワ
...and Towa in her new outfit.
っていうことでトワ尽くしになっておりますけれども
So it's a whole lot of Towa...
こちら、ことー先生に描いていただきました。可愛くない？
...and these were drawn by Koto-sensei. Aren't they cute?
いいぜ！ふー！これね、あの、いっぱい...実はね、本当はね
Nice! Whoo! Actually, the truth is...
アイドル衣装2種類とか、お正月衣装2種類とか色々書いてくれたんだけど
...they drew many variations like 2 types of idol outfits or New Year outfits...
もうめちゃめちゃ最後まで悩んでこの4種類にさせていただきましたので
...but I agonized over it until the very end and chose these four types.
皆さんよかったら、ランダムになってしまうんですけど
So if you'd like, they are random...
個別でも売ってるのでぜひ買ってください。
...but they're also sold individually, so please buy them.
はい、次！
Okay, next!
常闇トワモチーフ ボディバッグ
Tokoyami Towa Motif Body Bag
これこれ皆！ボディバッグ！
This one, everyone! The body bag!
これです！めっちゃこれ、この、これぐらいの大きさの胸ぐらいの、よくあるじゃない？
This is it! This size, about chest height, you see them often, right?
あるじゃない、なんかオバ...あれ、ちょっとオバ...よくあるでしょ？
You know, like... wait, a bit... you know what I mean, right?
そう、このね、リュックサックとかもいいなと思ったんだけど
Yeah, I thought a backpack would be nice too...
トワ結構この斜め掛けのミニポーチ、ちょっとした出かける時に
...but I really like these cross-body mini pouches for quick outings.
こういうバッグがすごい...個人的に、まあトワが欲しかったからっていうのもあるんだけど。
This kind of bag is great... personally, I wanted one too.
はい、このミニモチーフボディバッグも発売されます。
Yes, this mini motif body bag is also being released.
これめちゃめちゃね、あのね、普段使いできやすいような形で作成していただいてるので
This was made in a way that's very easy for everyday use...
ぜひよろしければどうぞ。
...so please check it out if you'd like.
基本的に全部あの個別で売ってるので、よかったら2個欲しいっていう方も個別で買ったりとかしてくださいね。
They're all sold individually, so if you want two, you can buy them that way.
眷属 3連ブレスレット
Kenzoku 3-Layer Bracelet
はい、じゃあ3つ目！ドーン！
Okay, third one! Boom!
はい、眷属3連ブレスレット！
Yes, the Kenzoku 3-layer bracelet!
これはね、ここの手首に、手首につけるやつでございます。
This is something you wear on your wrist.
オシャレだよね。トワのね、尻尾もイメージしてありますので
It's stylish, right? It's also designed with Towa's tail in mind...
イメージカラーと尻尾をブレスレットにしていただきました。
...so we made the image colors and the tail into a bracelet.
すごいグッズもね、トワがやっぱり、あの、普段使いできるようなのとか
For the goods, I really wanted things that can be used every day...
結構オシャレなものを今までグッズとして発売していたので
...since I've been releasing pretty stylish things as goods so far.
今回もオシャレなものが出したいんですっていう風にご相談したら
So when I said I wanted to release something stylish this time too...
オシャレにしてくれました！イェーイ！
...they made it look so stylish! Yay!
はい、じゃあ次！はい、どうぞ！
Okay, next! Here you go!
ビビマスク
Vivi Mask
はい、4つ目はマスク！はい、今のご時世大事です、皆さんどうぞ！
Yes, the fourth is a mask! It's important in this day and age, here you go!
次！はい、どうぞ！はい、全部買って...全部フルセットを買うと...
Next! Here you go! If you buy the full set...
あれ？そう、はい！
Huh? Right, yes!
フルセット購入特典：ことー描き下ろしダイカットポストカード
Full Set Purchase Bonus: Die-cut postcard drawn by Koto
こちら4種類のね、先ほどのミニイラストに、ミニイラストがね、あの、すごい、なんていうのこれ、あの、ダイカットっていうらしいよ。
Here are the four types of mini-illustrations from before. They're called 'die-cut' postcards.
のポストカードがついてきます。メッセージはね、秘密、秘密。
They come as a postcard. The message is a secret.
（笑）きも...秘密。きも...これです！皆。今日おかしいからさ
(Laughing) Kimo... secret. Kimo... this is it! I'm acting strange today.
ちょっと今スタッフさんにさ、ちょっとあの、苦笑いされながら説明してるから
I'm explaining this while the staff are giving me forced smiles.
すみません、これです！はい、ということでグッズセットがありますよっていうお話でした。
Sorry, this is it! So that was about the goods set.
今日おかしいんで、まあ昨日地獄味わってるから仕方ないよね？
I'm acting weird today, but I guess it can't be helped after experiencing hell yesterday.
ね、昨日というか今日、まあ昨日だよね。昨日ね、パパキンなんで、はい。
Right, yesterday... well, it was yesterday. Yesterday was PapaKin, so yeah.
はい、はい！ということで！ドドドド！告知はこれだけじゃないんです！
Yes! And there's more! Dum-dum-dum-dum! This isn't the only announcement!
重大告知が皆さんあるんです！では、重大告知、ドーン！ドーン！
There's a major announcement for everyone! Here it is, boom!
はい、常闇トワ 1st EP ミニアルバム『Scream』の発売になります！
Tokoyami Towa's 1st EP mini-album 'Scream' is being released!
常闇トワ 1st EP 「Scream」
Tokoyami Towa 1st EP 'Scream'
うおー！これ今誰も反応してくれないのがすごい寂しいけど
Whoa! It's so lonely that no one is reacting right now...
みんなのコメントを見て、トワはわーってなってるっていうことをすごい思います。はい。
...but I'm imagining everyone's comments and thinking 'Whoa!' Yes.
そあ、なんと目標でありましたアルバムを形に...
So, I've finally put my goal of an album into a tangible form...
…して出すことが決定しました！
...and it has been decided that it will be released!
すごい大変だった、すごいでもすごい楽しみでした。
It was really tough, but I was also really excited.
はい。ま、6曲収録されておりまして、
Yes. Well, it includes six tracks,
すりぃさんの「AKUMA」、R Sound Designさんの「ミッドナイト・ランウェイ」、
Surii's "AKUMA", R Sound Design's "Midnight Runway",
nikiさんの「Palette」と、あともう一曲ですね、「FACT」、
niki's "Palette" and one more song, "FACT",
あとANCHORさんの「Born to be real」と、
and ANCHOR's "Born to be real",
あと、うつPさんの「マイロア」の6曲、全部書き下ろしになってます。
and utsu-P's "My Roar" - all six songs are newly written.
こちらね、1月3日、今日ですね、9時、9時でいいんだよね、そう、9時に発売されます。
This will be released on January 3rd, today, at 9:00 PM, right? Yes, 9:00 PM.
概要欄ね、あのグッズもこっちの「Scream」のアルバムも、
In the description box, both the merchandise and the "Scream" album...
どっちもあの概要欄更新されてるので、9時になったら皆さんチェックしてください！はい！
both links in the description are updated, so please check them out at 9:00 PM! Yes!
はい、ということで、あ、ジャケット、ごめんなさい。ジャケットのデザインは、いづみ圭先生に、
Yes, and so... oh, the jacket design. I'm sorry. The jacket design is by Izumi Kei-sensei,
あとロゴは今日のね、あのロゴと一緒の、ま、柊先生に描いてもらってます。すみません。
and the logo is the same as today's logo, drawn by Hiiragi-sensei. Sorry about that.
ちょっと時間がね、ちょっと急ぎ足になってしまうんですけれども、はい、
Time is running a bit short, so I'm rushing a bit, but...
ではね、このアルバムどんな曲が入ってるのかと、皆さんちょっと疑問に思い方もいると思うので、
Yes, since some of you might be wondering what kind of songs are in this album,
これから歌っていきたいと思います。2曲、歌うので、
I'm going to sing them now. I'll be singing two songs,
ぜひ聴いてくれれば嬉しいです。じゃあ、聴いてください、「AKUMA」。
so I hope you'll listen. Well then, please listen: "AKUMA".
ジャスティス的なバイオレット
Justice-like violet
尖って参上　悪魔って最強
Appearing sharply, devils are the strongest
あなたの背中に闇をつけ
Attaching darkness to your back
小悪魔だって恐ろしい
Even a little devil is terrifying
完全極楽ついをご提示
Presenting the ultimate paradise pair
抗って最期　振り切って最強
Resisting until the end, shaking it off, strongest
淫らな少女　鎖つき
A lewd girl, bound with chains
悪魔に秘密の種つき
With a secret seed from the devil
何千回も爪を研いで　機を伺って
Sharpening claws thousands of times, waiting for the chance
洗脳完了　これで誕生
Brainwashing complete, thus born
永遠に尽くすだろう
Will serve for eternity
悪魔界連盟　はい繋いで
Devil World League, yes, connect
常闇がないなら　渦を巻く
If there's no everlasting darkness, it swirls
デビデビ　不可思議界面
Devi-devi, mysterious interface
ビビビビ　堕落の底から
Bibi-bibi, from the depths of corruption
人間界モードなんて　常識がないなら奪われる
Human world mode or such, if you lack common sense, it'll be stolen
デビデビ　悪魔なの
Devi-devi, I'm a devil
影を奪って　イェイ
Stealing shadows, yay
完全無欠のバイオレット
Flawless violet
切り込んでハイに　取り込んでワインに
Cutting in to get high, taking in to turn into wine
あなたの心に忍び込み
Sneaking into your heart
小悪魔だって恐ろしい
Even a little devil is terrifying
刻まないで　酔ってないならば
Don't carve it, if you're not drunk
他に誰　敵は誰
Who else, who is the enemy?
メンション限界　見つける錆
Mention limit, finding the rust
あれは君らナビ　対戦で
That's your navigation, in battle
悪魔界連盟　はい繋いで
Devil World League, yes, connect
相手にならないと　クダを巻く
If they're no match, I'll grumble
デビデビ　絶望照明
Devi-devi, despair illumination
ビビビビ　世界はフィクション
Bibi-bibi, the world is fiction
建前モードなんて　今だけは全てを占めない
Pretense mode or such, at least for now, don't occupy everything
デビデビ　悪魔なの
Devi-devi, I'm a devil
闇を知って　イェイ
Knowing the darkness, yay
消えない寂しさも　癒えない傷跡も
The loneliness that won't fade, the scars that won't heal
歩みを止めないなんて　法勝った人間は
Not stopping one's steps, humans who have overcome
時代を制覇洗脳して　光を生み出した
Conquering the era, brainwashing, and creating light
悪魔のような少女ね
A girl like a devil, isn't she?
ああ唸った文明で
Ah, in the groaning civilization
悪魔界連盟　はい繋いで
Devil World League, yes, connect
常闇がないなら　渦を巻く
If there's no everlasting darkness, it swirls
デビデビ　不可思議界面
Devi-devi, mysterious interface
ビビビビ　堕落の底から
Bibi-bibi, from the depths of corruption
人間界モードなんて　常識がないなら奪われる
Human world mode or such, if you lack common sense, it'll be stolen
デビデビ　悪魔なの
Devi-devi, I'm a devil
影を奪って
Stealing shadows
悪魔界連盟　はい繋いで
Devil World League, yes, connect
相手にならないと　クダを巻く
If they're no match, I'll grumble
デビデビ　絶望照明
Devi-devi, despair illumination
ビビビビ　世界はフィクション
Bibi-bibi, the world is fiction
建前モードなんて　今だけは全てを占めない
Pretense mode or such, at least for now, don't occupy everything
デビデビ　悪魔なの
Devi-devi, I'm a devil
闇を知って　イェイ
Knowing the darkness, yay
オーイヨエオ...
Oh-ee-yo-eh-oh...
マイロア
Myroa
やべぇなんかなりやべぇ 奴の奴隷だ
It's bad, somehow it's really bad, I'm a slave to that guy
野生のままでビルの谷間を行く
Remaining wild, I go between the buildings
ツノも ウロコも シッポも 触覚も
Horns, scales, tail, and antennae
出して 出して 出して 出したいのさ
Show them, show them, show them, I want to show them
群れから逸れ 理解されなくても
Straying from the herd, even if I'm not understood
好きなもので満たしたいだけ
I just want to fill myself with things I like
世界トップクラスで世界に一つだけの
World-class, and the only one in the world
役に立たない牙と爪
Useless fangs and claws
誰に言われたって変える気はねぇ
No matter what anyone says, I have no intention of changing
何語かわからない言葉で吠えろ
Howl in a language no one knows
オーイヨエオ...
Oh-ee-yo-eh-oh...
出せだせだせ 鬣(たてがみ)捨てて
Show it, show it, show it, throw away the mane
乱暴 アシメに どれもいいね
Wild, asymmetrical, they're all good
山も 谷も 空飛ぶの目指したなら
If you aimed to fly over mountains and valleys
敢えて羽を捨て走ってもいいね
It's okay to dare to throw away your wings and run
ライオンっぽくない ヒョウっぽくないって
Saying it's not like a lion, not like a leopard
人間のお偉いさんが決めたの？
Did some important human decide that?
世界トップクラスで世界に一つだけの
World-class, and the only one in the world
役に立たない牙と爪
Useless fangs and claws
正解(せいかい)だって跳ねて越える
Even 'correct answers', I'll jump over them
閉じ込められる場所なんてないのさ
There's no place I can be trapped
誰もお前は知らない
No one knows you
知ってるわけなんてない
There's no way they could know
チェックリストにも載ってない生物さ
A creature not even on the checklist
鼓動(こと)まで置いていけ
Leave even your heartbeat behind
君はどこまで見える？
How far can you see?
君はそこまで見る
You look that far
そこじゃないぜもっと
It's not there, it's further
世界トップクラスで世界に一つだけの
World-class, and the only one in the world
声になり損ねた牙と爪
Fangs and claws that failed to become voices
誰に言われたって変える気はねぇ
No matter what anyone says, I have no intention of changing
私の吠えだけの私の咆哮(ほうこう)
My howl, just for me, my roar
オーイヨエオ...
Oh-ee-yo-eh-oh...
はい！はい！どうでした？
Yes! Yes! How was it?
ゴリゴリなロックな曲、
A heavy rock song,
どうでしたでしょうか？はい。
how did you like it? Yes.
あの、すごいアイドル衣装でロックな曲とか似合わないとかそういう意見もあると思うんですけども、
Um, some people might think a rock song doesn't suit a cute idol outfit,
そんなね、概念をトワはこれからも、
But Towa wants to break through those concepts...
これからもというか、なんだろう、ぶち壊していきたいなと思っております！はい。
...from now on, or how should I say, I want to keep smashing them!
いろんなね、世界が見えたらいいなっていう気持ちを込めて、
With the feeling that I want to see various worlds,
今回のアルバムのタイトルは「叫び」「Scream」っていうタイトルにしました。
I titled this album 'Scream'.
でね、時間ももう来てしまったので、本当に本当に本当に本当にありがとうございます。
And well, the time has almost come, so thank you so, so, so much.
本当に本当にこうやって形にできたのは本当に皆さんのおかげだなと思っております。
I really think that I was able to make this happen thanks to everyone.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
はい。で、この後は、最後1曲披露したいんですけれども、
Yes. And after this, I want to perform one last song,
アルバムにね、収録される曲を歌います。
I'll sing a song that's included in the album.
9時からね、このあと9時から、投稿予約もしてるんですけれども
From 9 o'clock, right after this at 9 o'clock, I've scheduled a premiere...
プレミア投稿するので、そちらもぜひ見て聞いてくれたら嬉しいです。
...so I'd be happy if you could watch and listen to that as well.
はい、3年目も、アルバムも、
Yes, in my third year, and with the album too...
トワのこと、みんな本当に、よろしくお願いします！
...everyone, please continue to support Towa!
はい。では最後、nikiさんの作詞作曲、
Yes. Then for the last song, written and composed by niki...
FACT、聞いてください。
...please listen to 'FACT'.
常世の闇に 囚われたまま
Trapped in the darkness of the underworld
奏でる悲鳴を
Singing out a scream
聞かせて
Let me hear it
さあ 爪を磨いたら まだ子供のような あなたのために
Now, once I've sharpened my claws, for you who are still like a child
あぁ 試されたいなら その愚かな手に 手錠をかけて
Ah, if you want to be tested, put handcuffs on those foolish hands
常世の闇に 囚われたまま 甘い甘いガムを噛んでた
Trapped in the darkness of the underworld, I was chewing sweet, sweet gum
幾つもの不幸を さあ 捧げて
Offer up any number of misfortunes
さりげない合図に 隠れた 答えはすぐに 分からせてあげる
The answer hidden in a casual sign, I'll let you know it soon enough
微笑と嘘に まみれた 拒まないままに 受け止めてあげる
Covered in smiles and lies, I'll accept them without refusing
ほら 悲鳴を 聞かせて
Look, let me hear your scream
さあ 指を鳴らしたら この子猫のような 私のために
Now, once I've snapped my fingers, for me who is like this kitten
あぁ 喉が渇いたわ 唇の口に 指を散らして
Ah, I'm thirsty, scatter your fingers over the corner of my lips
狭い土牢に 閉じ込めたまま 首輪に繋がれたい
Kept locked in a narrow dungeon, I want to be tethered to a collar
下らないルールじゃ 奪えない 自由は既に この手の中にある
Useless rules can't steal it, freedom is already in these hands of mine
愛情では 測れない 弱ったままに 絡ませてあげる
It can't be measured with love, I'll let you entwine while you're weak
ほら 心を 開いて
Look, open your heart
分からないふりをして 寝惚けてるの？
Are you pretending not to know, are you half-asleep?
もっと 熱く 闇を見せてね
Show me a more intense darkness, okay?
さりげない合図に 隠れた 答えはすぐに 分からせてあげる
The answer hidden in a casual sign, I'll let you know it soon enough
微笑と嘘に まみれた 拒まないままに 受け止めてあげる
Covered in smiles and lies, I'll accept them without refusing
常世の闇に 刻む その名を 分からせてあげる
Carving that name into the darkness of the underworld, I'll let you know
ほら 悲鳴を 聞かせてよ
Look, let me hear your scream
夢見ないで ほら 聞かせて
Don't dream, look, let me hear it